Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- P-Series Manuscripts. (Box 34-59)
  - P-055b Partisan Warfare in Croatia. By Oberst Karl Gaisser; 76 pp, 7 illus; 1950. Similar to MS #P-055a, but more concise. (Box 41)
  - P-055c Lessons learned from the Partisan War in Russia. By Generalmajor Alexander Ratcliffe; 13 pp; 1951. A report by an expert on this type of warfare. (See also MS #P-142.) (Box 41)
  - P-056 Underwater Bridges. By General. der Infanterie Hans von Greiffenberg and 3 others; 26 pp, 2 illus; 1950. Clarifies the rumors on alleged Russian underwater bridges and describes similar German experiments. (Box 41)
  - P-057 Strength and Composition of German Artillery During World War II. By Generalmajor Kurt Scheffler; 21 pp, 10 illus; 1950. Answers to a special questionnaire on strength, expenditure of ammunition, and use of observation artillery, on specific dates in World War II. Answers are largely based on memory. (Box 41)
  - P-058 Events in Italy, 1 Feb.-8 Sep. 1943. By the Italian Generals Infante and Ambrosio; 35 pp; 1950. Answers to questionnaires on political and military affairs, particularly on the Italian attitude towards her German ally and a separate peace with Russia. (Italian text only; not translated- 1954.) (Box 41)
  - P-059 Tank Losses. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand; 28 pp, 7 illus; 1950. A statistical report on all German armored vehicles, giving nomenclature, characteristics, and quantities produced, together with data on tank losses and replacements. (Box 41)
  - P-060* Small Unit Actions During the German Campaign in Russian. See authors below; 289 pp, 51 maps, 40 illus; DA Pamphlet No. 20-269; 1953. A large number of interesting and instructive examples of action by the various combat arms, operating in all kinds of weather and terrain. Describes the development of German and Russian tactics during four years of war. This is an abridgment of the twenty-four studies listed below: (Box 41)
  - P-060a Small Unit Tactics-An Infantry Regiment in the East. By Oberst Guenther Drange; 184pp, 11 illus; 1951. (Box 41)
  - P-060b Small Unit Tactics-Manual for Command and Combat Employment of Smaller Units. By Generalferdmarschall Albert Kesselring and 5 others; 462 pp, 9 illus; OCMH multilith; 1952. A compilation of German experience in units below regiment size. (Box 42)
  - P-060c Small Unit Tactics-Engineers in Combat at River Sectors. By Generalmajor Erich Abberger; 47 pp, 11 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 11; 1952. A study of several river crossing operations in Russia, 1941. (Box 42)
  - P-060d Small Unit Tactics-Infantry. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 63 Part II pp, 10 illus; 1951. Examples of Russian attack tactics in winter. (Box 42)
  - P-060d Small Unit Tactics-Infantry. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 95 Part I pp, 9 illus; 1951. Examples of Russian infantry tactics and combat methods. (Box 42)
  - P-060d Small Unit Tactics-Infantry. By Generalmajor Wolf Ewert; 27 pp, Part III 7 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. 1, No. 5; 1952. Three examples of Russian reconnaissance in force. (Box 42)
  - P-060d Small Unit Tactics-Infantry: River Crossings. By Generalmajor Part IV Hellmuth Reinhardt; 14 pp, 6 illus Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 12; 1952. Three examples of Russian river crossing operations. Suitable for use in service schools. (Box 42)
  - P-060d* Small Unit Tactics-Infantry. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt. (In Part V preparation 1954.) (Box 42)
  - P-060f Small Unit Tactics-Tactics of Individual Arms. By Generalmajor Part I Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand and Generalmajor Oskar Munzel; 61 pp, 18 illus; 1951. Fourteen examples of German and Russian armored tactics. (Box 42)
  - P-060f Small Unit Tactics-Tactics of Individual Arms. By Generalmajor Part II Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand and 3 others; 174 pp, 27 illus; 1951. Six examples of Russian tank and antitank combat. P060-f Small Unit Tactics-Tactics of Individual Arms: Russian Tank & Part II Antitank Combat (Sketches). By Gen. Maj. Mueller-Hillebrand..... (Box 42)
  - P-060f Small Unit Tactics-Tactics of Individual Arms: Small German Part III Armored Units in Russia. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller- Hillebrand and 2 others; 38 pp, 20 illus; Hist Div UAREUR multilith; Vol. II, No. 11; 1953. Three examples froth the years 1941, 1942, and 1944. (Box 42)
  - P-060g Small Unit Tactics-Unusual Situations. By Generaloberst Erhard Raus; Part I 18 pp, 1 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 8; 1952. Combat in Lithuania, Jun 1941. (Box 43)
  - P-060g Small Unit Tactics-Unusual Situations. By Generaloberst Erhard Raus; Part II 29 pp, 3 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 13; 1952. Four examples from the Russian campaign. (Box 43)
  - P-060g Small Unit Tactics-Unusual Situations. By Generaloberst Erhard Raus; Part III 54 pp, 9 illus; Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 4; 1953. Stalingrad area; eleven examples from actions of the 6th Panzer Division, Dec. 1942. (Box 43)
  - P-060g Small Unit Tactics-Unusual Situations. By Generaloberst Erhard Raus; Part IV 98 pp, 7 illus; 1952. (Box 43)
  - P-060h Small Unit Tactics-Artillery. By General der Artillerie Karl Thoholte; Part II 94 pp, 15 illus; 1953. Two detailed examples, suitable for training purposes. (Box 43)
  - P-060h Small Unit Tactics-Artillery. By Oberst i. G. Hans-Georg Richert; 58 Part 1 pp, 6 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 7; 1952. Tactics and fire control of Russian artillery in attack and defense during 1941, 1942, and 1944, and their later development. (Box 43)
  - P-060i Small Unit Tactics-Attack Methods of Engineers. By Generalmajor Hans von Ahlfen; 54 pp, 12 illus; 1951. Two well chosen examples from the Russjan campaign, describing exercise of command, organization, technical equipment; sketches and photographs. (Box 43)
  - P-060j Small Unit Tactics-Small German Units in the Russian Campaign 1941-42. By Generalmajor Erich Schmidt; 15 pp, 5 illus; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 14; 1952. Three examples of successful improvisation. (Box 43)
  - P-060k Small Unit Tactics-Infantry Regiment in Attack. By Generalmajor Hans Kissel; 42 pp, 1 map; 1951. Attack and breakthrough of an infantry regiment at Slavyansk in spring 1942. (Box 43)
  - P-060l Small Unit Tactics-Unexpected Situations. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 14 pp, 4 illus; 1951. Supplements MS #P-060g. (Box 43)
  - P-060m Small Unit Tactics-Combats in Taiga and Tundra. By Oberstleutnant Klaus Brockelmann and Oberstleutnant Hans Roschmann; 151 pp, 14 illus; 1952. The fighting in Finland north of the Arctic Circle. (Box 43)
  - P-060n Small Unit Tactics-Fighting in Russian Forests and Swamps. By Oberst Wilhelm Willemer and 4 others; 50 pp, 21 illus; 1952. Examples of fighting in these undeveloped areas; Russian behavior; tactics. Well suited for use in service schools. (Box 43)
  - P-060o Small Unit Tactics-Engineer Attack on Fixed Fortifications. By Generalmajor Erich Abberger; 48 pp, 6 sketches, 7 photographs; 1953. Three examples showing the value of specially trained assault engineers. (Box 43)
  - P-061 Standing Operating Procedure for Troop Movements. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand; 6 pp; 1950. A short survey of German service regulations, pocket manuals, and books reveals that there were no instructions in the German Army covering operating procedure for troop movements. (Box 43)
  - P-062 Frostbite Problems in the German Army During World War II. By Generalmajor Alfred Toppe; 173 pp; 1951. A useful study on winter clothing and hygiene. Reasons are given for the lack of winter clothing in late 1941. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 43)
  - P-065a The Volksgrenadier Division and the Volkssturm. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 22 pp; 1950. A concise study on the organization of these two types of German units. An appendix by Mr. Hellmuth Heitmonn contains 9 pages of text and 25 charts, principally T/O & E's of subunits of the Volksgrenadier division. (Box 44)
  - P-065b TheVolksgrenadier Division and theVolkssturm. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 16 pp, 1 illus; 1950. Additional information on the infantry and artillery of the Volksgrenadier division. (Box 44)
  - P-066 Prefabricated Troop Shelters. By Generalmajor Alfred Toppe; 7 pp, 4 illus; 1950. Technical data on the German plywood and cardboard shelters for men and horses, copied from Finnish models. (Box 44)
  - P-071 Region, Climate, Population, and their Influence on Warfare in the Soviet Union. By General der Infanterie Friedrich Fangohr; 69 pp; OCMH multilith; 1951. Characteristics of European Russia as a war theater. (Box 44)
  - P-073 The Use of Private Property in Exercises and Maneuvers of the German Army in Peacetime. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 50 pp; Hist Div USAREU multilith; 1953. An account of the Army's rigid adherence to the laws and regulations protecting private property. (Box 44)
  - P-074 Demolitions and Mining. By Generalmajor Alfred Toppe and 8 others; 168 pp, 22 illus; 1953. A compilation of German experience in the use of mines and demolitions to delay Russians advances, 1942-44. Combat orders; establishment of special engr. headquarters; types of demolition; special techniques; methods of laying antitank and antipersonnel minefields. Two detailed examples are included: Operation BUFFALOwithdrawal of Ninth Army to the "Buffalo" position in March 1943; and the evacuation of the Kuban bridgehead by Seventeenth Army in September 1943. (Box 44)
  - P-077 Soviet Russian Infantry and Armored Forces. By Generalleutnant (Waffen-SS) Max Simon; 10 pp; Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 6; 1953. An evaluation of the Russian soldier and Russian combat methods. (Box 44)
  - P-079 The Russian Command in World War II. By Generalmajor Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 28 pp, 3 illus; OCMH multilith; 1951. A discussion of possible developments in the Russian command since 1945. The author cites shortcomings in the Russian wartime command and suggests improvements which may have been made. (Box 44)
  - P-080 Training of Senior Officers. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 22 pp; OCMH multilith; 1951. The scope and content of German courses for prospective division commanders and other general officers. Includes a 4- page commentary by Generaloberst Franz Haider. (Box 44)
  - P-082 Battle Command in the East. By Generalmajor Carl Wagener; 11 pp; 1950. Text of a report prepared in April 1944, when the author was chief of staff, First Panzer Army. .A plea to Hitler for a more flexible conduct of operations in the East. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 44)
  - P-083 Education of Officers. By Generalmajor Carl Wagener; 16 pp; 1950. A lecture to officer students during World War II. (Box 44)
  - P-085 Infantry Organization and Equipment Based on German Experiences in Russia. (CONFIDENTIAL) 174 pp; OCMH rnultilith; 1951. F-086 Long-Range Detonation. By Oberst Ludwig Korn and Oberst Kunibert Randewig; 28 pp, 1 illus; 1951. Russian use of radio-activated fuzes [sic] for long-range detonation. (Box 44)
  - P-087 Battle in Mud. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 10 pp, 1 illus; 1951. Brief examples of warfare during the muddy seasons in Russian. (Box 44)
  - P-088 Combat Missions for Panzer Training. By Generalmajor Oskar Munzel; 42 pp, 4 illus; 1951. Training maneuvers with and without live ammunition; proper commitment of armor. Brief accounts of four small unit actions which might be reenacted as maneuvers. (Box 44)
  - P-089 Tactical and Technical Specialities of Winter Warfare. By Generalmajor Oskar Munzel; 26 pp; 1951. A compilation of German experience in winter warfare. (Box 44)
  - P-090 German Employment of Horses on the Eastern Front. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand and 18 others; 776 pp; 1952. A detailed, comprehensive study of the procurement, training, employment, and management of draft and pack horses and cavalry remounts in the German Army. Emphasis is given to the use of horses in the Russian campaign. Valuable reading for a generation that has lost "horse-sense." (Box 45)
  - P-091 German EM and Company-Grade Officer's Wage Scale (1939-40). By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 17 pp; 1951. A statistical study based on the 1939-40 Army Administration Handbook. For lack of official documents the study cannot be considered completely accurate. (Box 46)
  - P-094 War Games. By General der Infanterie Rudolf Hofmann and 4 others; 207 pp, 2 illus; OCMH mimeograph; 1952. Administrative and technical problems in the conduct of all types of staff and command post exercises. Suitable for training at higher levels. (Box 46)
  - P-096 Concentration of Russian Troops for Stalingrad Offensive. By Barchewitz; 38 pp, 2 maps; 1951. Intercepted radio reports of Russian movements; describes the build-up of the German reconnaissance picture. (Box 46)
  - P-097 Selection and Training of German Officers for Military Attaché Duty. By Generaloberst Franz Halder and 9 others; 44 pp; 1951. A study of the prewar program, written by the then Chief of the General Staff and a group of acknowledged experts. (Box 46)
  - P-099 Refugee Control. By Generalmajor. Alfred Toppe and 14 others; 56 pp; OCMH multilith; 1952. An important study of a growing problem in modern warfare, based on wartime experience. A foreword by General Halder deserves special attention. (Box 46)
  - P-101 German AAA Ranges. By Intentant Dr. Albert Piske and Intendant Dr. Walter Schleyer; 12 pp; 1951. A short report on ranges in Germany, Austria, and Poland, 1939-45. (Box 46)
  - P-103 Utilization of Captured Materiel by Germany in World War II. By Generalmajor Helmuth Reinhardt and 5 others; 173 pp; OCMH multilith; 1953. The effect of captured materiel on fighting strength; the handling of such materiel; stresses the need for a special ordnance organization for this purpose. (Box 46)
  - P-105 Evaluation of German Airborne Operations. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt and 9 others; 165 pp; 1953. An evaluation of both actual and proposed German operations; a statement of the value and limitations of this arm. (Box 46)
  - P-107* Position and Defense Combats of a Motorized Grenadier Regiment in Winter 1941-42. By Oberst Wilhelm Reutter; 95 pp, 2 maps; 1951. Some examples of small unit tactics; the evaluation of the Russian soldier should be read with reservation. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 46)
  - P-108 Collaboration Between Germany and Her Allies During World War Part I II. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hiliebrand and others; 1116 pp; 1953. A detailed, comprehensive work based on documents and the personal recollections of the German participants. Part I is a general account of Germany's relations with her allies; Part II deals individually with each member of the Axis alliance. The study as a whole is an appreciation of the problems of coalition warfare. Valuable lessons are drawn from the German experience. (Box 46)
  - P-108 Collaboration Between Germany and Her Allies During World War Part II II. By Generalmakor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand and Others. (Box 46)
  - P-109c* Ardennes Follow Up-2d Panzer Division. By General der Panzertruppen Heinrich von Luettwitz; 3 pp; 1952. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 46)
  - P-109a* Ardennes Follow Up-3d SS Panzer Grenadier Regiment. By Oberstleutnant (Waffen-SS) Guenther Wisliceny; 20 pp; 1951. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-109b* Ardennes Follow Up-4th SS Panzer Grenadier Regiment. By Obersleutnant (Waffen-SS) Otto Weidinger; 28 pp; 1952. (Not translated- 1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-109d* Ardennes Follow Up-Arko 102. By Oberst der Schutipolizei F. W. Bock; 11 pp; 1952. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-109e* Ardennes Follow Up-2d Panzer Division (16-20 Dec. 1944 and 13-17 Jan. 1945). By Oberst Joachim Gutmann; 12 pp, 2 illus; 1952. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-109f* Ardennes Follow Up-10th SS Panzer Division. By Generalmajor (Waffen-SS) Heinz Harmel; 16 pp, 1 map; 1952. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-110 Barriers to the East. (CONFIDENTIAL) 16 pp, 2 illus; Hist Div EUCOM Mimeograph, Vol. I, No. 9; 1952. (Box 47)
  - P-113* Questionnaire on "Wehrmacht Propaganda." By Dr. Kurt Hesse; 6 pp; 1951. Answers to some questions on propaganda in occupied countries. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-114b* German Army Group Operations on the Eastern Front 1941-43, Central Area. By General der Infanterie Rudol Hofmann. (In preparation-1954.) (Box 47)
  - P-114c * German Army Group Operations on the Eastern Front 1941-43, Southern Area. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt. (In preparation- 1954.) (Box 48)
  - P-116 Russian Airborne Operations. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt and 10 others; 49 pp, 9 illus; Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 12; 1953. An account of the only two known operations involving Russian airborne troops with strategic and tactical missions. Possible reasons for the limited use of airborne troops by Russia. (Box 49)
  - P-119 Transportation of Replacements by Post Office Busses to the Eastern Front in Winter 1941-42. By Oberstleutnant Guenther Keil; 24 pp; 1954. An improvised method made necessary by the shortage of transport facilities. (Box 49)
  - P-122 German Counterintelligence Activities in Occupied Russia 1941-45. By Wladimir W. Posdnjakoff; 150 pp, 4 illus; OCMH multilith; 1953. The author is a Russian expatriate who served with the German intelligence service. (Box 49)
  - P-123 National Instinct and Governmental Institutions Under German Occupation in Western Russia. By Wladimir W. Posdnjakoff; 45 pp; 1951. Reactions of the Russian people to the German occupation. The observer is a Russian expatriate who served with the German intelligence service. (Box 49)
  - P-124 Zuyev's Republic. By Wladimir W. Posdnjakoff; 31 pp; 1951. An account of a small body politic created by Zuyev near Polotsk after the departure of the Communists in 1941. (Box 49)
  - P-126 Demolition of Tunnels. By Generaloberst Franz Haider; 3 pp; 1952. A report on the demolition of two railroad tunnels during the German withdrawal from Greece. (Box 49)
  - P-127 The Importance of the Narvik Region for Naval War. By Generaloberst Dr..Lothar Rendulic; 5 pp; 1952. (Box 49)
  - P-128 A German Panzer Battalion in the East, 1945. By Major Gert-Axel Weidemann; 10 pp; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. II, No. 3; 1952. A translation of an original combat report describing German and Russian armored and antitank tactics current at the end of the war. A close-up view of armored combat. (Box 49)
  - P-129 German Experiences in Desert Warfare During World War II. By Generalmajor Alfred Toppe and 9 others; 2 Vols; 380 pp, 36 sketches, 15 maps, 85 photographs; 1952. A comprehensive study based on German experience in North Africa. An extract has been published as Desert Warfare: German Experiences in World War II. 96 pp; OCMH multilith; 1952. (Box 50)
  - P-129 German Experiences in Desert Warfare During World War II. By Supp. Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein and Dr. Sigismund Kienow; 79 pp, 10 sketches, 3 maps, 31 photographs; 1952. Answers to specific questions on supply, especially water supply, with information on geology and well-drilling techniques. (Box 50)
  - P-130 Camouflage. By Oberst Wilhelm Willemer and 15 others; 239 pp, 49 illus; Hist Div USAREUR mimeograph; 1953. German methods of camouflage; the concealment of strategic and tactical intentions. (Box 50)
  - P-132 Signal Communications in the East. By General der NAchrichtentruppen Albert Praun; 238 pp, 36 sketches, 14 photographs; 1953. A detailed study by the former OKH Chief Signal Officer. Specific examples from Second Panzer Army and Army Group Center. (Box 50)
  - P-133 Analysis of US Reid Service Regulations. By Generaloberst Franz Halder and 6 others; 156 pp, OCMH mimeograph; 1953. A critique by a representative group of German generals and general stuff officers under the chairmanship of a former chief of the General Staff. Their analysis, based on official German military doctrine, includes definite suggestions for revising individual chapters and paragraphs of FM 100-5. (Box 51)
  - P-134 German Efficiency Report System. By General der Infanterie Rudolf Hofmann and 5 others; 97 pp, 2 illus; OCMH mimeograph; 1952. The development of this system from its inception to the end of the war, forms illustrating typical ratings are included. (Box 51)
  - P-135* The German General Staff, Part I. By Generalmajor Ludwig Ruedt von Collenberg. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 51)
  - P-135* The German General Staff, Part II (1918-45). By General der Infanterie Dr. Waldemar Erfurth; 554 pp; 1953. A comprehensive study by a leading German military historian and former member of the German General Staff. While in part colored by the author's personal experience, the study is based on recognized published works, a large number of unpublished sources, and on the memories of his colleagues. (Not translated-1954.) (Box 51)
  - P-136 The German Defense of Berlin 1945. By Oberst Wilhelm Willemer and others; 115 pp, 8 illus; 1953. A detailed account of the German defense, based on careful research. (Box 51)
  - P-138 Underground Activity in Kharkov 1941-43. By D. Karov; 17 pp; Hist Div USAREUR multilith, Vol. II, No. 7; 1953. An account of a successful resistance group. (Box 51)
  - P-142 Partisan Warfare: A Treatise Based on Combat Experience in the Balkans. By Generalmajor Alexander Ratcliffe; 94 pp; 1953. A synopsis of experience in this unique war theater. (See also MS #P-055a.) (Box 52)
  - P-143a Selected Army Operations on the Eastern Front. By General der Infanterie Rudolf Hofmann and others. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 52-53)
  - P-143c Selected Divisional Operations on the Eastern Front. By Oberst i.G. Wilhelm Willemer and others. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 53)
  - P-145 German and Russian Military Leadership During World War II. By Generalmajor Burkhart Mueller-Hillebrand. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 54)
  - P-148 Mountain Warfare: A Brief Treatise Based on Operations of 1st Mountain Division in the Caucasus, Aug.-Sep. 1942. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 60 pp; 1953. A synopsis of original reports prepared by the fighting troops immediately following action in the western part of the central Caucasus. (Box 54)
  - P-150 German Military Literature. By Generalmajor Heinrich Aschenbrandt; 42 pp, OCMH multilith; 1953. A brief survey of German military literature, with an annotated bibliography. (Box 54)
  - P-151 Operational Basis for the First Phase of the French Campaign in 1940. By Generaloberst Franz Halder; 20 pp, 2 illus; 1953. An account of the considerations and estimates that led to the strategic plans adopted for the first phase of the 1940 campaign. General Halder was then chief of the General Staff. (Box 54)
  - P-152 Ice Railway Bridge over the Dnepr. By Hauptmann Ludwig Schneller; 42 pp, 21 sketches, 25 photographs; Hist Div EUCOM mimeograph; 1953. A description of this interesting technical feat, completed despite much mistrust and opposition. (Box 54)
  - P-182* 346th Infantry Division, Oct. 1944. (Box 54)
  - P-191 Information on German Casernes in Reply to U. S. Seventh Army Inquiries. By Generalmajor Hellmuth Reinhardt; 12 pp; 1952. A report, based on memory, on the installations and facilities provided for various types of German units during the early part of World War II. (Box 54)
  - P-193 Denial of Airfields Through Demolitions and Other Means. (In preparation-1954.) (Box 54)
  - P-194 Organization of the Ground for Defense on a Broad Front, as Defended by an Army or Larger Unit. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 54)
  - P-195 Use of Floating Mines in Rivers Against Floating Bridges. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 54)
  - P-197 Problems, Lessons Learned, and Functions of Engineer Staffs of Army Groups. (In preparation--1954.) (Box 55)